Habib Waheed

07393 483727 | Manchester, England | habibwaheed10@hotmail.co.uk | https://github.com/HabibWaheed6

PROFILE

BSc (Hons) Software Engineering graduate at Manchester Metropolitan University. I have 4 years' worth of experience within the software development/engineering sector and self-taught myself programming. I have gained experience using many programming languages in my degree, online courses, and self-taught learning.

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

BSc (Hons) Software Engineering: Manchester Metropolitan University

2018-2022

Future Skills College - BTEC Level 3 Extended Diploma:

2017-2018

■ IT Coding : DDM (Distinction Distinction Merit)

BTEC Level 2

Door Supervisor Within the Private Security Industry

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Javascript, Python(.
 - Other Technical Skills: React(only a small bit of knowledge), Github, GIT, HTML, CSS, Set up Shopify store, word press, Agile Methodology, photoshop
 - PROJECTS COMPLETED
- I have a game on Google play: Mad Mamba run- Took an inspiration from Subway Surfers.
- I helped with completion of a website with company based in USA(Wordpress. Link for website is as following: https://theaestheticapp.online/
- Small blockchain- This was using python that me and a friend tried to make
- Personal website: www.HabibWaheed.com (HTML, CSS, Javascript, React)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Manager/Developer- HDesignEmporium

This is a company created by me and a friend. It is a freelancing company where we create apps and websites for people.

- Strong written and verbal communication: I communicate clearly with customers to understand and get a feels of what they need. This company has only been established for a couple of months.
- **High standards of work:** Since we focus on making sure the client requirement is met and the work is done to a high standard. We have to be upfront and keep on telling the client about the project etc.

Security Guard- (Different companies/Freelance) August 2020 - Present

- I have done security shifts in different places
- Strong Communication- I have learnt to communicate with different people and in different situations
- Alertness-Security is a demanding job and with this I have learn how to be alert and keep my eyes opened

- I did voluntary work at this agency.
- . I had to input data and make sure all the data inputted was correct and nothing was missed out
- I had to do all the administrative tasks- checking records and updating records
- I had to make sure email were also sent to the different clients, so they knew that everything had been done from our side

Door supervisor- ISSAT Security

Oct 2020 to present

- Strong written and verbal communication: I communicate clearly with everyone to help them with any problems and also making sure they are safe. I have been a door supervisor for over 2 years and I have been with multiple companies.
- High standards of work: I focus on making sure everyone is safe and if there is any problem, I can fix the problem without making it into a big deal, so everyone is safe and happy. I have to make sure no mistakes have been made and have to be alert at all times in case I see something which could be harmful to the civilians.
- Problem solving ability: I evaluate the problem by understanding what caused the issue and making sure it gets dealt with properly. Some problems can be language barriers, and some can just be people getting too drunk and starting fights.
- have good English, I was the one who had to translate to both the owner and client.
- Meeting and greeting the patients, during the covid pandemic(some shifts were in the hospital)
- Make sure that the right people arrive for their appointments and go to the right place.

•

Mobile Tablets | Work experience

December 2016 to February 2019

- Sales assistant: I had to just be a sales assistant and help customers find what they are looking for.
- **Fix Mobile Phones**: I had the responsibility of fixing mobile Phones and making sure it was done correctly without any further problems
- I took down customer details and had them noted down. The details were personal information which we needed to get in touch with the customer
- I also helped with translating and making sure that there wasn't a language barrier

PC World | Work experience

December 2016 to February 2017

Sales assistant: I had to just be a sales assistant and help customers find what they are looking for.

Volunteer | Mechanic

June 2014 to September 2016

- Help: I was the assistant and whenever possible I tried to do the car service myself
- Translate: I was a translator for when a client who couldn't speak Urdu came. Since the owner was a
 Pakistani and didn't have good English, I was the one who had to translate to both the owner and
 client.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE AND SKILLS

UDEMY: I started to learn in-depth about Web development. I learnt about the complex concepts of the course, and I further enhanced my learning by completing challenges and creating projects for myself but also trying to make websites for clients. I also enrolled onto other courses such as React courses and Python courses which I am planning on completing within this year.

Languages:

English (Native), Urdu (Fluent).

REFERENCES

References available upon request.